所以我们要进入下一节，就是命名空间，对。
So we're gonna go on to the next section
now, which is namespaces, right.
到目前为止我们一直在担心文件系统
So far we've just been worrying
about the file system, but
我们还没担心其他事情对吧
we haven't been worrying
about other things, right?
所以如果我有两个 chroot 的环境
So if I have two chroot'd environments
next to each other, right,
他们其实还能看到对方的过程，对吧 ?
they can actually still see
each other's processes, right?
所以如果在一个 chroot的环境里，我说，对，
So if inside of one chroot'd environment,
I say ps, right,
这就是你我能在这里看到的
which is how you I can
actually see that right here.
这说明我有这个跑步和这个跑步，对吗 ?
This shows me that I have this running and
this running, right?
这是在任何特定时间运行的两个进程，对吗 ?
These are the two processes
running at any given time, right?
所以如果我在每个树根的环境里都这样做
So if I do this within each
chroot'd environments,
假设他们都有必需品图书馆
assuming that they both had all
the necessaries libraries and
都能看到对方的过程，对吧 ?
all that kind of stuff, they can
see each other's processes, right?
那么再次，如果我是 A 公司， B 公司也在里面，
So again, if I'm Company A, and
Company B is also running in there,
A 公司可以说
Company A can just say.
你知道吗 ?
You know what?
杀了他们的网络服务器对吧
Kill their web server, right?
因为他们可以看到对方的过程，对吗 ?
Because they can see each
other's processes, right?
好像是有问题的吧
Seems like it would be problematic, right?
这就是名称空间。
So that's what namespaces are.
名称空间是这些的概念
Namespaces are these the idea of these
我们可以限制每一个 Linux 的不同层面
various different facets of Linux that we
can limit each one of these particular,
支持这些监狱进程以写入或使用这些容器环境。
prop these jails processes to write or
these container environments.
所以我可以说，哎，你只能看到自己的过程，自己的过程
So I can say, hey, you can only see your
own processes and you get your own process
还有你自己的网络层，你不能和别人一起乱搞。
IDs, and you get your own networking layer
and you can't mess with anyone else's.
你只能把自己的环境弄得一团糟
You can only mess with
your own environment.
所以我要做一些我要讲的故事 -f 我的新根或秘书。
So I'm going to do something I'm gonna
say tale -f my new root or secret.txt.
所以这事要做什么
So what this is gonna do,
现在就要开始一个漫长的过程了吧
this is gonna start a long
running process right now, right?
所以它只是在运行这个尾巴
So it's just running this tail-secret.txt,
这会给这个带来什么东西，它就会开始显现。
what this does is anything added to this,
it would start showing that.
但我只是为了给你看看
But I'm just doing this to show you,
如果事情只是漫长的过程的话会发生什么
what happens if something is
just a long running process.
我要开另一个空壳
I'm gonna open another shell here.
我将连接到同一个 Docker 环境。
And I'm going to connect to
that same Docker environment.
我要说 Docker exec -it， Docker -host bash。
So I'm going to say Docker exec -it,
Docker -host bash.
这将在同一容器中打开另一个 shell 。
This is going to open another
shell in the same container.
好了，现在 1 和 2 都连接到同一个容器。
Right, so now 1 and 2 here are both
connected to the same container.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
所以如果我说的是 ps ，你可以看到，它的运行也一样。
So if I say ps here, you can see,
That it has the same things running.
好吧我要做的是 ps
Right, cuz I have to do ps aux.
你可以看到它有尾巴 -f，对吧 ?
So you can see here it has tail -f, right?
所以为了看这个，我得要求更多的东西，对吗 ?
So in order to see that,
I had to ask for more things, right?
这就是你的工作
That's what the aux does.
你可以在这里看到
So you can see here,
我有一个 PID 103 ，它是另一个过程中运行的尾巴。
I had this PID 103 which is the tail
that's running in the other process.
所以，如果我说，码头工人会杀了人，或者不去码头，对不起，杀死 103人。
So if I say, docker kill, or
not docker, sorry, kill 103.
现在，如果我回到这里，注意到这个停止了，对吗 ?
Now if I go back over here,
notice that this stopped, right?
上面说是终止的对吧
It says, Terminated, right?
那是因为其他的
That's because from the other
我刚说过要杀死那个程序对吧
connected shell I just said
kill that process, right?
这就是我们想要防止的问题，对吧 ?
So this is the issue that
we want to prevent, right?
我们想防止人们彼此之间发生这种事。
We want to prevent people from
doing this to each other.
这就是名称空间让我们可以做的事情，对吗 ?
And so that's what namespaces
allow us to do, right?
所以，如果我有两个不同的过程。
So if I have these two
different processes.
我可以说，哎，这个你看不出这里发生了什么，反之亦然
I can say, hey, this one you can't see
what's happening over here and vice versa
我们会用一个叫它的环境来做对吧
and we're gonna do that with a environment
called, yeah, with namespaces, right?
这就是我们要做的我们要用一个叫不分享的命令
That's what we're gonna do and
we're gonna use a command called unshare.
好了，所以我就在同一个容器里，我的新根在这里。
All right, so So I'm here in my same
container, and I have my new root here.
我要创造更好的根
I'm actually going to
create a better root,
我要教你怎么做
and I'm gonna show you how to do this.
所以我想让你做的第一件事就是正确的更新。
So the first thing I want you
to do is say, apt-get update.
这将转至并更新您可以下载的软件包的列表。
This is gonna go and update your list
of packages that you can download.
这应该可以，你可以看到它会下载 11 兆字节。
This should take, you can see
it's gonna download 11 megabytes.
然后就这样了
And that did that.
我们会说很恰当的安装
And we're going to say apt-get install
我和你的人在我的工作中
deboostrap and I was, I debootstrap
TST 总是把我搞上去
that TST always messes me up, -y.
又这个小的，下载了几个工具
And again this little,
download a couple of tools so
我们可以用一个叫 debootstrap 的学校而不是去
that we can use a school called
debootstrap instead of having to go and
把所有这些都复制了
hand copy all of these various different.
它会下载一些东西这些不同的工具
It's gonna download a few things,
all these various different tools,
一到一看他们的李斯就能得到正确的东西
one by one and looking at their
libs to get the right things.
我要给你演示如何使用一个叫 DBootstrap 的工具
I'm going to show you how to use a tool
called DBootstrap that's just gonna set
全新的完全有效的更改可读环境。
up an entirely new,
totally valid change readable environment.
既然你下载了 DBootstrap 我们会说
So now that you've downloaded DBootstrap,
we're gonna say, dbootstrap,
--变体，对等 ( minbase )
--variant, Equals minbase which is
只下载你最不需要的工具
gonna download just the, the most minimal
amount of tools that you need possible.
你可以告诉你 Ubuntu 或 devant 为您下载的是什么。
You can tell what kind of you Ubuntu or
deviant to download for you.
我要说仿生，因为这就是我们使用的 18.04。
I'm gonna say bionic because that's
what we've been using 18.04.
但你可以说在这里伸展它会工作伸展是 Debian
But you can probably say stretch here,
and it would work, stretch is Debian,
不是 Ubuntu， Ubuntu 基于 Debian ( 如果您不知道 ) 。
not Ubuntu, Ubuntu is based on
Debian if you're not aware of that.
好吧我要把它做得更好一点你也知道
Okay, and I'm gonna put that into slash
better root and again just so you know
这将会有大约 150 兆字节的下载值，这样就可以知道了。
this is gonna do about 150 megabytes worth
of download so just be aware of that.
如果那是你的事你就可以看
If that's a thing for you,
then you can just watch and
你会得到大部分的而不必亲自去做
you'll get most of this without
having to do this yourself.
所以我要跑了
So I'm going to run that.
这可能要考虑一下你的网络有多快
This is gonna take probably about,
depending on how fast your Internet is,
大概三到五分钟吧
up to three to five minutes, maybe?
希望因为我们的网络很快
Hopefully, since we have
pretty fast Internet here,
这只需要一分钟
this should only take a minute.
但实际上这会给你做些什么
But what this is actually gonna go do for
you is it's going to get a bare minimum
您需要运行基于 Debian 的 Ubuntu的文件系统。
set of a file system that you need
to run a Debian based Ubuntu.
所以， Bootstrap 实际上是 Debian 引导程序。
So DBootstrap is actually
Debian bootstrap.
所以当他们为 Debian 和 Ubuntu 建造容器时
So when they're building containers for
Debian and for Ubuntu,
他们实际上是用这个工具来引导一个全新的环境。
they actually use this tool to
bootstrap a brand new environment.
它的意思是你可以直接把它直接插入其中。
It and it's done with the idea that
you can chroot directly into it.
所以他们实际上是用这个来建造 Ubuntu 之类的东西。
So they actually use this to like
build Ubuntu and stuff like that.
所以我们是为了自己的目的而合作
So we're kind of co-opting it for
own nefarious purposes.
所以现在这个是 bootstrap， dbootstrap，对吧 ?
So now this is finished bootstrapping,
dbootstrapping, right?
所以如果我有更好的根
So if I go into better root.
你可以在这里看到，基本上是我在这里看到的一切，对吧 ?
You can see here, it's got basically
everything that I saw up here, right?
它有一个 tmp， var， usr， sys， srv， run，所有这些东西，对吗 ?
It's got a tmp, var, usr, sys, srv,
run, all that kind of stuff, right?
所以现在我可以说改变路线点在这条更好的路线上。
So now I can say change route dot right
to be inside of this better route dash.
你可以看到一切都在这里
And you can see here it
everything works now
因为它有各种不同的工具。
much better because it has all
of the various different tools.
所以我看着里面有 bin，你可以看到我有点，
So I look inside have bin,
you can see I have quite a bit,
我能用得更多的工具
quite a bit more tools
that I can use right.
其实我内心的变化就更难看出来
In fact it's kind of even hard to tell the
difference of am I inside of the change
在正常环境中的根环境还是我
root environment or
am I inside the normal environment?
很难看出来
It's hard to tell.
好的。
Okay.
所以现在我可以摆脱这一点，回到正常的状态。
So now I can get out of this,
and I'm back into the normal one.
现在我们要做个叫不分享的事对吧
And now, we're gonna do
something called unshare, right?
所以我要说不分享
So I'm gonna say unshare.
在这里我要告诉它所有东西都不能分享
And here I have to tell it
everything to unshare from this
我正在创作的新过程
new process I'm creating right.
我是说不共享网络不共享文件系统
So I'm saying unshare the network,
unshare the file system,
与流程管理系统正确的 UTF 不共享吗 ?
unshare the UTF which is like
the the process managing system right?
所以我要说不共享的破折号安装，所以不共享所有安装。
So I'm gonna say unshare dash dash mount,
so unshare all the mounts.
作为进程 IPC 的 UTS ，我不记得当时是什么。
The UTS which is the processes IPC, which
I cannot remember what is it at the time.
网络，是进程标识的 PID ，
The network,
the PIDs which is the process IDs,
我又不记得了
fork which again I don't remember,
用户喜欢所有用户部件，映射 root 用户。
users like all the users parts,
the map root-user.
好的，然后你会告诉它如何用那个不共享的环境来运行。
Okay, and then you're gonna tell it what
to run with that unshared environment.
所以我想说我想在树根里这么做
So I'm gonna say, run chroot, and
I wanna do it in /better-root,
我要你去跑巴什
and I want you to run bash, right.
所以这个树根部分，应该是你熟悉的。
So this chroot part,
that should look familiar to you.
这正是我们以前所做的但现在我们只是在增加
That's exactly what we were doing before,
but now we're just adding unshare,
[INAUDIBLE] 取消共享所有这些名称空间，对吗 ?
[INAUDIBLE] unshare all these name spaces,
right?
所以我现在就在这个，对，如果我看的是 ps ，它会说，
So now I'm in this, right, and
if I look at ps aux, it's gonna say,
hey，您需要先安装流程系统。
hey, you need to mount
the process system first.
所以说吧
So go ahead and
在你的树根环境里和我一起运行这些命令。
run these commands with me as well
inside of your chroot'd environment.
我想说安装 -t proc none /proc ，用于进程。
I wanna say mount -t proc none /proc,
which is for processes.
我们要再做一次
And we're gonna do it again for
sysfs， sysfs 无/系统。
sysfs, sysfs none/sys.
并安装 -t tmpfs 无 /tmp。
And mount -t tmpfs none /tmp.
好吧既然我们已经这样做了我们可以说
All right, so now that we've done that,
we can say ps aux, and
我们可以在这里看到它自己看不到，对吧 ?
we can see here that it cannot
see outside of itself, right?
你看这个 bash，对，我们现在都是 PID 的
You look here that this bash, right, the
bash that we're in at the moment is PID
这就是我们所期望的，对吧 ?
one, which is what we would expect, right?
但那是在不共享的树根环境中运行的那个。
But that's the one that's running inside
of the unshared, chroot'd environment.
这不是在外面跑的人
It's not the one running outside of it.
事实上如果我们回到另一个壳
In fact,
if we come back to our other shell,
如果我们说 PS 的话我们就能连接到这个了
that we've connected to
this if we say PS aux.
我们可以看到不分享的，我们可以看到巴什，
We can see the unshare,
we can see the bash,
我们甚至可以看到那些正在运行的东西
we can even see all that kind
of stuff running cuz we can.
从主人的身体里我们可以看到孩子的内心
From the host,
we can see inside of the child but
孩子自己看不到，对吧 ?
the child cannot see outside of itself,
right?
所以让我们说如果我说的是尾巴
So let's say if I say
again did the tail fs or
tail- F my rootsecret.txt 权限，因此现在再次运行。
tail- F my rootsecret.txt right so
now this is running again.
如果我回到另一个环境，我说 PS aux 仍然看不到它，对吧 ?
If I go back to the other environment and
I say PS aux still can't see it, right?
如果我说尾部 F 让我们说点文字
And if I'd say tail F,
let's just say touch text or
text.txt 和 I 表示尾部破折号
text.txt and I said tail dash
来这里的 F.
F.txt that come here, stop this.
我又说了，你可以看到这个可以看到它的尾巴，因为它是
And I say ps aux again, you can see
this one can see the tail because it's
父进程正在查看未共享的环境。
the parent process looking
into the unshared environment.
你也可以看到这个混蛋
You can also see this bash here,
就是在不共享的环境中运行的那个
which is the one that's running down
inside of the unshared environment.
PID 其实是 7536对吧
It's PID is actually like, 7536, right?
所以它确实会把这些坑映射到宿主的环境中。
So it actually does, it maps these
pits to the host environment.
现在我要给你展示一下正确的过程吗
Now I'm showing you just processes right?
我们实际上没有分享网络
We actually unshared the network,
我们在这个环境中分享了很多其他的东西
we unshared a bunch of other
stuff in this environment so
它确实是按它可以访问的名称空间来进行集装箱化的，对吧 ?
it is truly containerized in terms of
the name spaces that it can access, right?
所以如果我想把它连接到网络上
So if I wanted this to be able to connect
to the network I would actually have to
在此创建单独的网络并将其连接到主机网络，
create a separate network inside of here
and connect that to the host network,
然后连接到更广的网络，对吧 ?
which then would connect to
the broader network, right?
我不打算教你怎么做，主要是因为，我不知道怎么做。
Not going to show you how to do it, mostly
because, I'm not really sure how to do it.
我可以弄明白但需要一段时间
I could figure it out but
it would take a while and
这就像开车回家一样
this is kind of to drive
home the point that.
您可以取消共享这些名称空间功能，对吗 ?
You can unshare these
namespace capabilities, right?
所以，更改路由就像我在共享文件系统对吗 ?
So change routing is like I am
sharing a file system right?
名称空间是有关来自这些特定进程的共享功能或
Namespace is about sharing capabilities
from these particular processes or
控制流进入这些流程的能力，对吧 ?
controlling the capabilities that
flow into these processes, right?
这很合理
It makes sense.
>> And Brian，为什么需要您运行安装命令?
&gt;&gt; And Brian, why do we need
you to run the mount command?
那是什么 然后，经常共享。
What did that do?
Do, often then shared.
>> 所以，安装一个，这样环境就能知道
&gt;&gt; So, the mount one, so that
the environment could know like taking
资产，流程系统和系统文件系统。
assets and the process system and
the system file system.
它本身并不是自动完成的。
It doesn't do that
automatically by itself.
而当你启动 Ubuntu 过程时，它会为您做这些事情。
Whereas, when you start up the Ubuntu
process, it does do that stuff for you.
因此，您只需要将所有这些不同的功能安装到
So, you just have to like mount all
this various different capabilities to
操作系统。
the operating system.
告诉他这就是你找到这些东西的地方
It just tell him,
this is where you find the stuff.
>> 通常的库会说话，索引就在那里。
&gt;&gt; Kind of the usual library so
to speak, the index just go there there.
> > 是。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
你有个问题
You had a question.
>> 因此终止进程的退出命令也会除去
&gt;&gt; So the exit command that terminates
the process, does that also get rid of
完全创建的容器( 在您的终端退出时 ) 吗 ?
the profusely created container,
at all, when you exit on your terminal?
> > 嗯，那如果我回去的话，让我们看看这个
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so if I went back,
let's see, to this one and
我说出口会终止这种不共享的环境
I said exit here, this would
terminate this unshared environment.
我们回到过去的地方对吧
And we go back to wherever it was, right?
所以在这件案子里我只是直接从主持人的
So in this case because I'm just
doing it directly from the host,
它会把我送回宿主
it would send me back to the host.
但如果你和我的电脑连接我想限制你
But if you're connecting to my computer
and I want to limit you, I would just have
如果你退出，它就会完全退出连接。
it if you exit it, it would just
exit out of the connection entirely.
>> 将是靠后仰的命令来查看我有多少个容器 ?
&gt;&gt; Would be the housecleaning command
to see how many containers I have?
如果我想管理他们
If I want to manage them,
删除一些，你一般是怎么穿过他们的 ?
delete some, how do you usually
go to navigate through them?
通常，
&gt;&gt; So typically,
你不会像这样用手制造容器对吧
you're not gonna be creating
containers by hand like this, right?
这是一个浪费的过程
This is a wildly wasteful process,
这比你能做的事更有学术水平
it's more an academic exercise
than something you would ever do.
Docker 有一堆能为你做的事对吧
Docker has a bunch of stuff that
just does that for you, right?
有个东西说 Docker PS
So there's a thing says Docker PS, and
我会给你们展示所有的容器
I'll show you all of
you running containers.
这能回答你的问题吗
Does that answer your question?
太酷了
Cool.
我们回去再讲一个有趣的练习
Let's go back to tell just one
more fun exercise I'm telling this
短信也一样吧
text thing as well, right?
如果我再做 Docker ，或者不说话，查看我的所有运行过程。
And if I do Docker or not talker ps aux
again, to see all my running processes.
你可以在这里看到我能在这里拿这个 PID
You can see here that I can actually
grab this PID right here and
我完全可以说杀掉 7555对吧
I can totally say kill 7555, right?
如果我回到不共享的环境里
Now if I go back over here inside
of the unshared environment,
都被终止了对吧
it's been terminated, right?
因此，主机仍然可以控制在子进程中发生的所有内容，但是
So the host can still control everything
that's happening in the child process, but
孩子的过程没看出来，挺有意思的。
the child process can't see out of it,
which is kinda fun.
我完全可以终止整个会议
And I could totally just
terminate the entire session.
事实上，我们也要这样做，对吧 ?
In fact, let's do that as well, right?
同样地，如果我做了 ps ，你可以看到这个是 PID 1，
Again, here if I do ps aux,
you can see this is PID 1,
但如果我回到这里
but if I come back over here and
我说我不知道为什么我一直想那样做
I say, I don't know why I keep
wanting to do that, docker ps aux.
如果我来这里我说 7356 我说杀了 7356
If I come here and
I grab 7356 and I say, kill 7356.
你会注意到如果我们回到这里就能完成整个过程
You'll notice if we come back here,
it's done, it killed the entire process,
你可以直接杀死整个集装箱
you can actually just kill
the entire container.